hey guys this looks like a fun one it
gives us that this is 9 this is 16 and
this is 12 and they're all at right
angles with each other and it wants us
to find the radius of this quarter
Circle if you want to try it on your own
pause it right now cuz I'm going to
solve it in 3 2 1 for the first step
let's extend this over here and we're
completing this rectangle this bottom
will be equal to the top which is nine
and this side will be equal to this side
which is 16 and we've created this
little piece right here let's call that
X next let's draw two of our radi one
from here to here and one from here to
here and these are both radi so we'll
call them R first I want to focus on
this triangle right here this is a right
triangle so we can use the Pythagorean
theorem it'll be x + 16 2 + 9^ 2 is
equal to R 2 and then let's do the same
thing for this triangle down here it'll
be 9 + 12 2 + x^2 is = R 2 and we can
clean this up a little bit this 9 + 12
inside of the parentheses can be 21 and
now we have two equations with two
variables so let's solve for these
variables this is equal to R2 and that's
equal to R2 so we can set this equal to
that on the left hand side 212 is equal
to 441 and we can bring down the x^2 on
the right hand side this x + 16 2 is
equal to x + 16 * x + 16 and after we
multiply that out it ends up being x^2 +
32x + 256 and then this 9^ 2 is equal to
81 next let's subtract x^2 from both
sides of the equation on the left hand
side we have the 44 1 and then on the
right hand side we can bring down the
32x and 256 + 81 is equal to 337 let's
smush everything together and we want to
get this X all by itself so let's
subtract 337 from both sides of the
equation on the left hand side 441 - 337
is equal to 104 and on the right hand
side these will cancel each other out so
we're left with 32x next we can divide
both sides by 32 on the left hand side
both of these have eight in common so
it'll simplify to 13 over4 and on the
right hand side these 32s will cancel
each other out leaving us with X and now
we've solved for X it's equal to 13
over4 and let's update this x to be 13
over4 and we can also update this x to
be 13 over4 and now we're ready to solve
for R 212 is equal to 441 and this 13
over 4^ 2 that's the same thing as 132
over 4^2 which is equal to 169 over 16
and then we can copy down the R 2 in
order to add these two let's make this
441 a fraction by doing 441 over 1 to
give them a common denominator we can
multiply top and bottom of this by 16
and both of these 16s will just hop
right over to the fraction 16 * 441 is
equal to 756 and 16 * 1 is equal to 16
and now that these have the same
denominator we can write them as a
single fraction and 756 + 169 is equal
to
7,225 next we can square root both sides
of the equation on the left hand side
this square root can be split to top and
bottom the square root of
7,225 is equal to 85 and on bottom the
square root of 16 is equal to 4 and on
the right hand side the square root and
the square will cancel each other out
and then 85 / 4 is equal to
21.25 and now we found the radius to our
quarter Circle it's equal to
21.25 CM this is the answer to our
question let's put a box around it how
exciting